《异形2》
Bio readouts are all in the green。Looks like she's alive.
生命迹象指数全为绿色，看来她还活着
Well，there goes our salvage，guys.
只找到她，各位
- How are we today？- Ohh。Terrible.
- 今天觉得如何？- 糟透了
Well，better than yesterday，at least.
至少比昨天好多了
- Where am I？- You're safe.
- 这是那里？- 你很安全
You're at Gateway Station。Been here a couple of days.
你已在基地休息了数天
You were pretty groggy at first，but now you're okay.
你有点虚弱，但现在已没事了
Oh，looks like you've got a visitor.
看来有人来拜访你
Jonesy。Come here.
乔西，过来
Hey，come here.
过来
How are you，you stupid cat？
你好吗？你真是只笨猫
How are you？Where have you been？
你去那里了？
Guess you two have met，huh？I'm Burke。Carter Burke.
我想你们必定已会过面，卡特巴特
I work for the company，but don't let that fool you。I'm really an okay guy.
我是公司的人，别被我骗了，我是好人
I'm glad to see you're feeling a little better.
真高兴见到你好多了
They tell me that all the weakness and disorientation should pass soon.
他们说你的虚脱很快会好
That's just natural side effects of such an unusually long hypersleep，or something like that.
那只是过度长眠的自然影响
What do you mean？
那是什么意思？
How long was I out there？
我漂流了多久？
Inhalation Therapy，report to-
吸入疗法…
Has no one discussed this with you yet？
还没有人跟你说过吗？
No。But，I mean…
没有…
I don't… recognize this place.
我可真的不认得这地方
No，I know。Uh-
我知道
Okay。It's just that，uh，this might be a shock to you.
好吧，你可能会吓一跳
- It's long - How long？
- 因很久了 - 多久了？
Please.
请说
- 57 years。- What？
- 57年 - 什么？
That's the thing。You were out there for 57 years.
你在外面漂流了57年
What happened was you had drifted right through the core systems.
你被漂流到航道外
And it's really just blind luck…
拯救队能找到你…
that a deep-salvage team found you when they did.
已经好运
It's one in a thousand，really.
千分之一的机会率
I think you're damn lucky to be alive，kiddo。You could be floating out there forever.
你能活着真是幸运，你可能会永远漂流在外太空
You-You okay？
你还好吧？
You okay？
你还好吗？
Oh-h-h！Oh，God！
老天！
- Nurse！Please！- God！
- 护士，快来！- 天啊！
Someone get in here now！
快来人！
Now！
马上！
- Hold！- Please.
- 捉住她 - 求求你
Hold on！
捉住她
Kill me！
救救我！
No！
不要！
Bad dreams again？You want something to help you sleep？
又做恶梦了？你需要安眠药吗？
No.
不
I've slept enough.
我睡够了
Jonesy.
乔西
Come here.
过来
Shh.
嘘
It's all right.
没事了
It's all right now.
It's over.
结束了
Dr Hirsch，334。Dr。Hirsch，334.
赫许医生，请到334号！赫许医生，请到334号！
Hi。Sorry I'm late。I've been running behind all morning.
抱歉，我迟到了，我整个早上都好忙
Is there any word about my daughter？
我的女儿有没有消息？
Uh… I really think we should worry about the hearing now.
我们应该先谈听证会的事
'Cause we don't have a lot of time，okay？I read your deposition，and it's great.
我们时间不多，我看过你的证供，很不错
If you just stick to that，I think we'll be fine。The thing to remember is，
你只要坚持你的说法，应该不会有问题的
there're gonna be a lot of heavyweights in there.
会有很多重要人物到场
You've got feds and Interstellar Commerce Commission，
包括调查局，星际贸易委员会
Colonial Administration，insurance company guys.
殖民地行政主管，保险公司
Do you have any news about my daughter？
你有没有我女儿的消息？
Well，we did come up with some information。Why don't we sit down？
我们的确查到了一些消息，坐下来谈吧
I was hoping to wait until after the inquest.
我本来想等到审判之后再告诉你
「Amanda Ripley-McClaren」，married name，I guess…
「阿曼达·蕾普莉·麦克伦」，应该是夫姓吧？
「Age 66.」
66岁
And that was at the time of her death，
那是她死亡的时间
which was two years ago.
是两年前的事了
I'm real sorry.
我很遗憾
Amy.
阿曼达
She was cremated and interred at Westlake Repository，Little Chute，Wisconsin.
她火葬后埋在威斯康辛
No children。I checked.
没有子女，我查过了
I promised her… that I'd be home for her birthday.
我答应她，她生日的时候会回家
Her 11th birthday.
陪她过十一岁生日
I'djust like to go，uh…
我们得谈谈
back to this point about the override destruct order.
拒绝毁弃条例的事
- Is it in the file？- I don't understand this.
- 是不是在文件里？- 我不懂
We have been here for three and a half hours.
我在这儿三个半小时
Now，how many different ways do you want me to tell the same story？
同一件事你要我说多少遍？
Look at it from our perspective，please.
你得替公司着想，请坐
Please？
请坐
Now，you freely admit to detonating the engines of，
你坦白表示引爆船舰
and thereby destroying，an M-class starsreighter，
因此摧毁的太空船
a rather expensive piece of hardware.
价值连城
Forty-two million in adjusted dollars.
共值四千二百万元
That's minus payload，of course.
这还不包括货物
The lifeboat's flight recorder corroborates some elements of your account，
救生船记录证实你的部分证供
in that，for reasons unknown，the Nostromo set down on LV-426，
不明原因使诺斯托罗莫号迫降LV426
an unsurveyed planet at that time，that it resumed its course…
该星球不适合生存，太空船再度启程后…
and was subsequently set for self-destruct by you for reasons unknown.
却被你以不明原因自动引爆
Not for reasons unknown。I told you.
不是不明原因，我已经说过
We set down there on company orders to get this thing，which destroyed my crew…
我们奉公司命令去带回异形，它消灭我的队员…
and your expensive ship.
和你那艘昂贵的太空船
The analysis team，which went over the lifeboat centimeter by centimeter，
分析化验小组，地毯式搜索，发现
found no physical evidence of the creature you describe.
被你消灭的东西没有生命迹象
Good！That's because I blew it out of the goddamn air lock，
很好，因为我把它抛出气舱外
like I said.
跟我说的一样
Are there any species like this hostile organism on LV-426？
LV426星球，是否有这种生物存在？
No。It's a rock。No indigenous life.
没有，只有岩石，没有生物
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply while I was away？
难道我的智商在长眠时衰退了？
Ma'am，I already said it was not indigenous.
我说过，那不是当地的生物
It was a derelict spacecraft。It was an alien ship.
是外星船
It was not from there。Do you get it？We homed in on its beacon.
异形不是那儿来的，懂吗？我们收到它们的信号
And found something never recorded once…
结果找到三百多个报告里…
in over 300 surveyed worlds.
都没有的玩意
- 「A creature that gestates inside a living human host.」 - Yes.
- 一种活在人体内的怪物 - 是的
These are your words。「And has concentrated acid for blood.」
这是你的说法，它的血液有强酸性，对吗？
That's right.
没错
Look。I can see where this is going，
听着，我知道发生什么事
but I'm telling you that those things exist.
不过我要说的是怪物的确存在
- Thank you，Officer Ripley。That will be all。- Please。You're not listening to me.
- 谢谢，足够了，蕾普莉 - 拜托，你没听进去
Kane，the crew member-
凯恩是我的队员
Kane，who went into that ship，said he saw thousands of eggs there.
他进去看过，有上千个异形的卵
- Thousands。- Thank you。That will be all.
- 上千个 - 谢谢你，别说了
Goddamn it，that's not all！
该死，我还没说完！
Because if one of those things gets down here，then that will be all！
要是有一只侵入，我们就真的完了！
Then all of this-this bullshit that you think is so important-
你和这些你认为很重要的废话
You can just kiss all of that good-bye！
便真的完了！
It is the finding of this court of inquiry that…
本庭判决…
Warrant Officer E。Ripley，
蕾普莉军官
NOC14472，
军籍号码NRC14472
has acted with questionable judgment…
因做出不当判断…
and is unfit to hold an I.C.C。license as a commercial flight officer.
所以不适合持有ICC执照，并担任星际飞行官的任务
Said license is hereby suspended indefinitely.
所以我们将永久吊销其执照
Now，no criminal charges will be filed against you at this time，
目前将不会以任何罪名起诉你
and you are released on your own recognizance…
不过你将接受…
for a six-month period ofpsychometric probation，
六个月的心理治疗
to include monthly review by an I.C.C。psychiatric technician.
并每个月接受ICC心理医师的检查
These proceedings are closed.
休庭
（资料封锁）
That could have been better.
你应该冷静点
- Look，I think the-Ripley？- Van Leuwen.
- 听着，蕾普莉？- 范·卢恩
Why don't you just check out LV-426？
你何不查查LV426区？
Because I don't have to。There have been people there for over 20 years，
没有这个必要，那里有人工作二十年以上
- and they never complained about any hostile organism。- What do you mean？What people？
- 从来没说过有敌人 - 什么意思？什么人？
Terraformers。Planet engineers.
星球改造者，工程师
They go in，set up these big atmosphere processors to make the air breathable.
他们去装设大气工程，以便有空气呼吸
Takes decades.
花了十年的时间
It's what we call a 「Shake 'N Bake」 colony.
这就是我们所说的外星殖民地
How many are there？How many colonists？
有多少人？有多少殖民地？
I don't know-60，maybe 70 families。Do you mind？
不知道，大概有60到70户，借过
Families.
有住户？
Jesus.
天啊
I'll be down in maintenance，okay？Al！
我到下面维修部去，艾尔
- What？- Hey，Al.
- 什么事？- 嘿，艾尔
- What？- Remember you sent some wildcatters…
- 干嘛？- 你记不记得你上个礼拜…
out to the middle of nowhere last week，out past the Ilium Range？
派人到髂骨区调查的结果？
- Yeah，what？- One of them's on the horn，a mom-and-pop survey team.
- 记得，怎么了？- 有人回报说他们找到些东西
He says he's onto something。He wants to know if his claim will be honored.
想知道结果有没有他一份
Why wouldn't his claim be honored？
为什么不呢？
Well，because you sent them to that particular middle-of-nowhere on company orders，maybe.
因为是你派他到那个鬼地方去
- I don't know。- Christ！Some honch in a cushy office on Earth…
- 我也不清楚 - 天啊，我们只是…
says，「Go look at a grid reference.」
奉上级的命令行事
We look。They don't say why，and I don't ask.
他们也没有解释原因，我也不会多问
I don't ask，because it takes two weeks to get an answer out here，and the answer is always-
我不问是因为要等两个星期才有答案，而答案总是
「Don't ask.」
「不要多问」
So what do I tell this guy？
我要怎么跟他说呢？
Tell him as far as I'm concerned，if he finds something，it is his.
告诉他，据我个人意见，他找到的东西就归他
- Lydecker？- What？
- 莱特克 - 干什么？
You kids know you're not supposed to be on this level！
小孩不可以到这里来！
Go on！Get outta here！
快走！
Do too。You go in places we can't fit.
你专门跑到我们去不了的地方
So？That's why I'm the best.
那又怎么样？谁叫我比你好
Knock it off！I catch either of you playing in the air ducts again，l'll tan your hides.
别闹了，别让我再抓到你们两个到不该去玩的地方玩
Mom，all the kids play-
妈，所有的小朋友都…
Wait a minute。Annie，come and have a look at this，will ya？
等等，安妮，过来看看
Folks，we have scored big this time.
我们这次挖到宝了
What is it，Dad？
那是什么啊？
I'm not sure.
我不知道
Let's see if we can't get a closer look at this thing，
看看我们能不能靠近一点看
maybe through that crack there on the side.
也许还有入口
Shouldn't we call in？
我们该先向基地报告吧？
Let's wait till we know what to call it in as.
先看看这东西到底是什么
That's about as close as we can get.
我们只能靠这么近了
Should we take a look inside？
要不要进去看看？
You two stay inside。I mean it。We'll be right back.
你们两个留在里面，我们马上回来
- Okay。- Bye.
- 好的 - 再见
Timmy，they've been gone a long time.
蒂米 他们去了好久
It'll be okay，Newt。Dad knows what he's doing.
他们不会有事的，爸爸知道他在做什么
Mayday，Mayday！This is Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner calling！
求救！求救！AK249呼叫！
This is Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner！
AK249呼叫！
Alpha Kilo Two Four Niner calling！
Hiya，Ripley。This is Lieutenant Gorman…
嗨，蕾普莉，这是殖民地的…
of the Colonial Marine Corps-
戈曼中尉
Ripley，we have to talk.
蕾普莉，我们得谈谈
We've lost contact with the colony on LV-426.
我们与LV426失去联络
I don't believe this.
我真的不能相信
You guys throw me at the wolves，and now you want me to go back out there？
你们曾丢我去那儿，现在又叫我回去？
Forget it。It's not my problem.
免谈，这不是我的问题
- Can I finish？- No。There's no way.
- 我可以说完吗？- 不，没可能
Ripley，you wouldn't be going in with the troops.
蕾普莉，你不必跟随军队进去
I can guarantee your safety.
我保证你的安全
These Colonial Marines are very tough hombres.
这些殖民陆战队都是顶尖的
They're packing state-of-the-art firepower.
拥有最尖端的火力装备
There's nothing they can't handle.
什么状况都能应付
- Lieutenant，am I right？- That's true.
- 中尉，对吗？- 完全正确
We've been trained to deal with situations like this.
接受训练就为了应付这种状况
Then you don't need me。I'm not a soldier.
你们不需要我，我不是军人
Yeah，but we don't know exactly what's going on out there.
可是我们不知道情况如何
It mayjust be a downed transmitter，okay？
也许只是通讯器故障
But if it's not，I would like you there as an adviser，
如果不是的话，我希望你做我们的顾问
and that's all.
就这么简单
What's your interest in all this？Why are you going？
这件事对你有什么好处？你为什么要去？
Corporation cofinanced that colony，
那个殖民地是我们出资支持的
along with Colonial Administration.
同时也是我们管理的
We're getting into a lot of terraforming now。「Building Better Worlds」-
我们现在要进行广大的开垦计划，建造一个更好的世界
Yeah，yeah。I saw the commercial.
我看过广告了
Look，I don't have time for this。I've got to get to work.
我没时间跟你搞，我还有事要做
Oh，right。I heard you're working the cargo docks.
是了，听说你在货柜码头工作
That's right.
对
- Running loaders and forklifts，that sort of thing？- Yeah。So？
- 忙着装货补货吗？- 是呀，怎样？
Nothing。I think it's great that you're keeping busy.
没事，让自己忙一点很好
And I know it's the only thing that you could get.
我知道你也只能干这种差事
There's nothing wrong with it.
这没有什么不对
What would you say if I told you I could get you reinstated…
如果我能使你再当…
as a flight officer？
飞行官呢？
- The company's already agreed to pick up your contract。- If I go.
- 公司方面同意和你签约 - 只要我肯去
Yeah，if you go.
对，只要你肯去
Come on。That's a second chance，kiddo.
来吧！第二春呢
I think，personally，for you，it would be the best thing in the world…
而且我认为必须要去面对…
to get out there and face this thing，get back on the horse.
你才有机会克服
Spare me，Burke。I've had my psych evaluation this month.
放过我，我刚看过心理医生
Yeah，I know。I've read it。You wake up every night。Your sheets are soaking with sweat-
我知道，我读过你的报道，你每晚醒来直冒冷汗
I said no，and I mean it！
我说不就是不！
Now，please leave。I am not going back.
请你走吧，我不回去
And I am-I would not be any good to you if I did.
我回去对你也没有好处
Okay。Shh.
好吧
Would you do me a favor？Just think about it.
帮我个忙，考虑一下
Thanks for the coffee.
谢谢你的咖啡
Hello.
你好
Ripley.
蕾普莉
- You okay？- Just tell me one thing，Burke.
- 你还好吧？- 告诉我一件事，巴克
You're going out there to destroy them，right？
你要去毁灭它们，对吗？
Not to study，not to bring back，but to wipe them out.
不是研究，也不是带回来，而是消灭它们
That's the plan。You have my word on it.
这就是了，我保证
All right。I'm in.
好吧，我去
I think that-
我想…
And you，you little shithead，
至于你，小混蛋
you're staying here.
你留下来
They ain't payin' us enough for this，man.
他们这次付的钱还不够多
Not enough to have to wake up to your face，Drake.
不够把你叫醒吗？
What？
什么？
Is that a joke？
这是笑话吗？
Oh，I wish it were.
希望是
Hey，Hicks。Man，you look just like I feel.
希克斯老兄，你的样子就像我这么逊
All right，sweethearts。What are you waiting for？
大伙，等什么？
Breakfast in bed？Another glorious day in the corps.
等人送饭吗？又是全新的一天
A day in the Marine Corps is like a day on the farm…
陆战队的日子就像农场物语
every meal's a banquet，every paycheck a fortune，every formation a parade.
吃得好，赚得多，还能大干一场
- I love the corps！- Christ！
- 我爱死陆战队 - 天啊
Man，this floor is freezing！
地板冰死人了
- What do you want me to do？Fetch your slippers for ya？- Gee，would you，sir？I'd like that.
- 你要我怎样？帮你拿拖鞋？- 可以吗？那最好
Look into my eye。Fall in，people.
看着我，集合了，大伙
Come on。Let's go.
快点
I hate this job.
我不喜欢这差事
Crowe，Wierzbowski。Come on。On your feet。We got some slack coming，right？
快点，威伯斯基，快起来，你的腿抽筋了？
You had three weeks on your back，Frost。What do you want？
干完这活就有三周休假，法斯，你要什么？
I'm talking about breathing，not this frozen shit.
我要呼吸顺畅，不是睡在冰冷的盒子里
Yeah，Top。How 'bout it？
头儿，这样如何？
All right。First assembly's in 15，people。Shag it.
到十五区开会，过去集合
Hey，mira。Who's Snow White？
米拉，白雪公主是谁？
She's supposed to be some kind of consultant.
应该就是女顾问
Apparently，she saw an alien once.
显然，她曾经见过异形
Whoopee-fuckin'-do！Hey，I'm impressed.
真有一套，我真佩服她
iQue bonita！
我不敢相信！
Hey，Vasquez。Have you ever been mistaken for a man？
娃丝佳，你被误认成男人吗？
No。Have you？
没有，你呢？
Ha，ha！Oh，Vasquez。You're just too bad.
娃丝佳，你真是太悍了
Hey，Top，what's the op？
老大，什么任务？
It's a rescue mission。You'll love it.
救援行动，你会喜欢的
There's some juicy colonists' daughters we have to rescue from their virginity.
我们要解救殖民地，移民女儿的贞操
Dumb-ass colonists.
移民笨蛋
- What's this crap supposed to be？- Vasquez.
- 这是什么烂东西？- 娃丝佳
Corn bread，I think。It's good for you，boy。Eat it.
玉米饼吧，对你有好处，吃吧
Hey，sure wouldn't mind getting some more of that Arcturian poontang.
我不介意再找一些肉蛋
- Remember that time？- Yeah。Except the one that you had was male.
- 记得吗？- 对呀，你那只是公的
Doesn't matter when it's Arcturian.
当是肉蛋没有关系
- Hey，Bishop，man。Do the thing with the knife。- Oh，please.
- 主教，表演一下吧 - 饶了我吧
Oh，come on。Yeah.
快呀，来吧
All right！Yeah.
好的
- I don't want to see that，man。- Come on，man。All right。All right.
- 我不要看 - 来啊，好样的
Hey，what are you doing，man？What are you doing？
你在干嘛？老兄，你在干嘛？
- Come on。Quit messing around，Drake。- Hudson，shut up ！
- 别搞我，垂克 - 哈德森，闭嘴！
- Bishop，hey，man。- Do it，Bishop！
- 主教，老兄 - 动手，主教
- Hey！Not me，man！Quit messing around！- Yeah，you！Don't move.
- 我不要 - 别动
Trust me.
相信我
All right。Knock it off，knock it off.
好了，别闹了
Thank you.
谢谢你
There you go，short shit。Enjoy your meal.
矮冬瓜，吃你的晚餐吧
That wasn't funny，man.
这不好笑
- Lieutenant Gorman？Mr。Burke？- Yeah，thanks.
- 戈曼中尉？巴克先生？- 好，谢谢
Looks like the new lieutenant's too good to eat with the rest of us grunts.
新任中尉不肯跟我们同桌吃饭
Boy's definitely got a corncob up his ass.
落水狗上岸，抖起来了
Thought you never miss，Bishop.
我以为你从不会失手，主教
You never said anything about an android being on board。Why not？
你怎么不早说船上有生化人？
It never-never occurred to me.
我没想到
It's just common practice。We always have a synthetic on board.
这很平常，船上一向都有生化人
I prefer the term 「artificial person」 myself.
我比较喜欢被称为「人造人」
Right.
对
- Is there a problem？- I'm sorry.
- 有问题吗？- 抱歉
I don't know why I didn't even-
我不知道为什么…
Ripley's last trip out，the syn-the artificial person malfunctioned.
蕾普莉上次因生化人造人故障
- Malfunctioned？- There were problems and a few deaths were involved.
- 故障 - 发生问题，有些人被害死
I'm shocked。Was it an older model？
真是想不到，旧的那一型吗？
The Hyperdyne Systems 120-A2.
120-A2型
That explains it then。The A2s always were a bit twitchy.
这就难怪，A2型常常有问题
That could never happen now with our behavioral inhibitors.
现在我们这些新生代不会有这种情形
It is impossible for me to harm，or by omission ofaction，allow to be harmed，a human being.
我绝对不会伤害人类
You sure you don't want some？
你真的不要？
You just stay away from me，Bishop。You got that straight？
离我远点，主教，明白吗？
Guess she don't like the corn bread，either.
我猜她也不喜欢玉米饼
- Squad，ten-hut！Officer on deck！- As you were.
- 部队立正，长官驾临 - 稍息
Quickly，quickly。Settle down.
快点！快点！站好！
All right。Listen up！
好了！听好！
Morning，marines。l'm sorry we didn't have time to brief you people before we left Gateway-
早安，陆战队员，很抱歉离开基地前没时间说明
- Sir？- What is it，Hicks？
- 长官 - 什么事？希克斯
Hudson，sir。He's Hicks.
是哈德森，长官，他才是希克斯
What's the question？
什么问题？
Is this gonna be a stand-up fight，sir，or another bug hunt？
这是一场战斗还是除虫行动？
All we know is that there's still no contact with the colony…
目前只知道还没和移民联络上…
and that a xenomorph may be involved.
还有一种异形侵入
- Excuse me，sir。A what？- A xenomorph.
- 抱歉，什么？- 异形
It's a bug hunt.
这是除虫行动
- What exactly are we dealing with here？- Ripley.
- 敌人到底是谁？- 蕾普莉
I'll tell you what I know.
我会把经过说出来
We set down on LV-426.
我们降落在LV426
One ofour crew members was brought back on board with something attached to his face，
队员把附在脸上的东西带回去
some kind of parasite.
类似寄生虫的东西
We tried to get it off。It wouldn't come off.
我们试着弄下来，可是没办法
Later，it seemed to come off by itselfand die.
后来好像脱皮而死
Kane seemed fine.
肯恩的气色不错
We were all having dinner，and，um，
我们一起用晚餐
it must have laid something inside his throat，some sort of embryo.
它一定在他体内产卵
- He started-Um，he - Look，man.
- 然后他就开始… - 听着，大姐
I only need to know one thing-where they are.
我只想知道它在哪里？
- Yo，Vasquez。Kick ass。- Anytime，anywhere.
- 干掉它 - 随时随地
Right，right。Somebody said 「alien.」 She thought they said 「illegal alien」 and signed up.
有人一提到异形，她就以为是非法移民
- Fuck you，man。- Anytime，anywhere.
- 去你的 - 随时奉陪
Are you finished？
够了没？
I hope you're right。I really do.
希望你说的对，真的
Yeah，okay，right。Thank you，Ripley.
好了，谢谢你，蕾普莉
We also have Ripley's report on disk。I suggest you study it.
磁碟片上也有蕾普莉的报告，我建议你们研究一下
Because just one of those things managed to wipe out my entire crew in less than 24 hours.
那只异形在24小时内消灭我全船人员
And if the colonists have found that ship，then there's no telling…
如果移民发现那艘船，不知道…
how many of them have been exposed.
有多少只已经在活动
Do you understand？
明白吗？
Anyway，we have it on disk，so you better look at it.
全都在磁碟片上，最好去看看
Any questions？
还有问题吗？
What is it，Private？
什么事？二等兵
How do I get out of this chickenshit outfit？
我该怎么脱离这胆小部队？
You secure that shit，Hudson.
给我闭嘴，哈德森
All right.
好吧
Now listen up.
现在听好
I want this thing to go smooth…
我要大家按规矩…
and by the numbers.
好好地干
I want D.C.S。and tactical database assimilation by 0830.
早上八点半携带战略资料
Ordinance loading，weapons strip and drop-ship prep details…
全副武装，全体动员…
- will have seven hours。- Oh，come on.
- 离行动时间有七小时 - 又来了
Now，move it，people！
动手吧，各位！
All right，sweethearts。You heard the man，and you know the drill.
好的，甜心们，你们听到中尉的话
Assholes and elbows！Hudson，come here。Come here.
赶快行动，哈德森，过来，给我过来
I don't care if you are short，Hudson。Get it done.
我不管，哈德森，快去做
Hey，Sarge。You'll get lip cancer smoking those.
士官长，抽雪茄会得口腔癌
Corporal，I want this loading lock sealed。Now！
下士，我要这舱口关闭，快点！
- How many more you got，Spunkmeyer？- Last one.
- 还有多少没弄好，史都麦？- 最后一个
Good。Take it away.
把它弄好
Clear behind.
小心后面
Did you check number three？Let me see that.
检查过3区吗？我来看看
Hi。I feel like kind of a fifth wheel around here。Is there anything I can do？
我在游手好闲，可以帮忙吗？
I don't know。Is there anything you can do？
我不知道，你能做什么？
Well，I can drive that loader.
我能操作起重机械人
I have a Class 2 rating.
我有2等级数
Be my guest.
请便
Where you want it？
放哪儿？
Bay 12，please.
请放到12区
All right，sweethearts。We're a team，and there's nothing to worry about.
好的，甜心们，你们是一队，没什么好担心的
We come here，and we gonna conquer，and we gonna kick some.
我们前来是要奋力杀敌
- Is that understood？That's what we gonna do，sweethearts。- Yes，sir.
- 明白吗？这就是我们的任务 - 明白
We are going to go and get some。Hey.
咱们就这么干，大家好好表现
All right，people！On the ready line！
好了，到预备位置！
- Are you lean？Are you mean？- Yeah！Yeah！
- 你们狠吗？够狠吗？- 是！
- What are you？What are you？- Lean and mean！
- 你们是什么？- 陆战队！
Hudson！Get on the ready line，marine！
哈德森！到预备位置！
Get some today！Get on the ready line！
动身了！到预备位置！
Yo！Move it out！Move it out，goddamn it！
快！快！快！妈的！
Get hot！One，two，three！Get out，get out，get out！
动起来！1、2、3！走！走！走！
Move it out，move it out，move it out！Move it out，move it out，move it out！
走！走！走！走！走！走！
Absolutely badasses.
真是一群悍将
Let's pack 'em in。Get in there！
上车了，进去！
All right！Move it！
快点！
Let's go，let's go！One，two，three，
上车！上车！1、2、3
four，five，six！
4、5、6人！
All right。I want combat seating。You know your places.
好了，战斗位置，大家都知道
Get those weapons stowed。Let's go.
武器放好，快
Come on。Settle down，people.
大家坐好
Lock 'em in，Hudson.
锁好，哈德森
Ready to get it on？You know it！
上路吧！
Okay，Bishop，let's go.
主教，起飞吧
Roger.
收到
I'm ready，man.
我准备好了，哥儿们
Ready to get it on！Go！
准备大干一场！走！
Stand by。Cross-locking now。Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
预备，锁门，闸门关闭
Primary couplers released。Hit the internals.
主连结器脱离，开启主动力
- Shit，man。- Confirm cross-lock and drop stations secured.
- 见鬼 - 确认锁紧及发射安全
Affirmative。All drop stations secured.
确定发射安全
Stand by。Ten seconds.
预备，十秒钟
Stand by to initiate release sequencer… on my mark.
照我的口令，准备发射
- Five，four，three，- We're on an express elevator to hell，going down.
- 5…4…3… - 我们正在下地狱，下去了
two，one，mark.
2…1…发射
- Switch to D.C.S。ranging。- 240，nominal to profile.
- 转到DCS地形图 - 表面纵剖面图240度
We're in the pipe，five by five.
我们上5X5航道
We're picking up some hull ionization.
正通过电离层
Got it。Rough air ahead.
前面有乱流
We're in for some chop.
正冲过去
How many drops is this for you，Lieutenant？
中尉，你有几次飞行经验？
Thirty-eight.
38次
Simulated.
模拟飞行
How many combat drops？
几次战斗经验？
Uh，two… including this one.
两次，包括这次
- Shit。- Oh，man！
- 惨了 - 天啊！
Range 014。Turning on final.
014度，准备降落
And I'm telling you，I got a bad feeling about this drop.
我告诉你，我有个坏预兆
You always say that，Frost。You always say，「I got a bad feeling about this drop.」
你老是这么说：「我有个坏预兆」
Okay，okay。When we get back without you，
好吧，万一你回不去
I'll call your folks.
我会通知你父母
All right。Let's see what we can see.
好了，让我看看
Everybody online。Looking good.
大家都在，精神很好
Drake，check your camera。There seems to be a malfunction.
垂克，你的电眼好像故障
That's better。Pan it around a bit.
好多了，移动一下
- Good。- I'm ready，man。Check it out.
- 好 - 准备好了，你们看
- I am the ultimate badass。- Yeah。That's right.
- 我是最强战士 - 是的，没错
- State-of-the-badass art。You do not want to fuck with me。- Who here's runnin'？
- 铁血悍将，最好别惹我 - 谁是这里的头儿？
Check it out.
你看
Hey，Ripley，don't worry.
蕾普莉，别担心
Me and my squad of ultimate badasses will protect you.
我和我的兄弟会保护你的
Hey！That's right.
嘿！没错
Check it out.
看
Independently targeting particle-beam phalanx.
这是独立瞄准粒子枪系统
Fry halfa city with this puppy.
包准把异形烧成焦炭
We got tactical smart missiles，
还有导弹系统
phase-plasma pulse rifles，R.P.G.'s.
还有最先进的太空武器
We got sonic，electronic ball breakers！
还有超音波电子枪！
We got nukes，we got knives，sharp sticks-
我们有核子武器，还有刀具，很锋利
Knock it off，Hudson。All right，gear up.
别闹了，韩森，大家准备好
Two minutes，people。Get hot.
2分钟，各位准备行动
Somebody wake up Hicks.
把西克斯叫醒吧
Coming around for a 709er.
接近709度
- Terminal guidance locked in。- Where's the damn beacon？
- 自动导航锁定 - 该死的信号在哪里？
Oh，I see it.
看到了
- That's the atmosphere processor？- Yep，that's it.
- 那就是大气处理机？- 没错，就是它
Remarkable piece of machinery。Completely automated.
顶尖的科技，全自动化
You know，we manufacture those，by the way.
我们也生产这玩意
Okay，Ferro。Take us in low over the main colony complex.
好，弗洛，带我们到殖民地的主要区域
Storm shutters are sealed.
雨窗关闭
There's no visible activity。All right。Hold at 40.
没有可见活动，好，稳住40英里前进
- Roger。- Give me a slow circle of the complex.
- 知道 - 慢慢绕着建筑物飞
Structure seems intact。They still have power.
结构似乎完整，他们仍有电力
Okay，Ferro。Set down on the landing grid.
好了，弗洛，降落吧
Immediate dust off on my clear，then stay on station.
清除视觉障碍，随时待命
Down and clear.
可以发动
Ten seconds，people。Look sharp.
十秒钟，提起精神
All right。I want a nice，clean dispersal this time.
咱们来个漂亮分散队形
Let's go！Move it out！
走吧！快点！
Head 'em up！
来吧！
First squad up on line。Hicks，get yours in accord and watch the rear.
第一队就位，希克斯，你殿后
Vasquez，take point。Let's move！
娃丝佳带头，前进！
Move up.
前进
Hudson，run a bypass.
哈德森，把电门弄开
Second squad，move up。Flanking positions.
第二队前进，掩护队形
Second squad on line.
第二队就位
You set？
好了没？
Go on.
前进
Second team，move inside。Hicks，take the upper level.
第二队往里面走，希克斯，搜上面的通道
Sir，you copying this？Looks like hits from small-arms fire.
长官，你看到吗？看来是被轻型武器攻击
Uh，we got some explosives damage.
像是地震引起的
It's probably seismic survey charges.
爆炸损害
Are you reading this？Keep it tight，people.
你听到吗？跟紧点
All right。Hicks，Hudson，use your motion trackers.
希克斯，哈德森，用你们的行动追踪器
Nothing。Not a goddamn thing.
什么迹象都没有
Quarter and search by twos.
两人一组搜索
Okay。Dietrich，Frost，you're up.
迪特里希，法斯，你们上
It's right in there.
就在里面
Now！Now！
马上！
Good one，Hudson！
干得好，哈德森！
Uh，sir，uh，we have a negative situation here。Uh，movin' on，sir
长官，里面没有可疑情况，我们继续搜索
Wait。Wait，tell him to-
等等，叫他们…
Hicks，back up。Pan right.
希克斯，后退，镜头移向右边
- There。- You seeing this all right？
- 看这里 - 看得到吗？
Looks melted。Somebody must have bagged one of Ripley's bad guys here.
像是被腐蚀过，看来是杀死蕾普莉队员的东西
Acid for blood.
硫酸血？
If you like that，you're gonna love this.
你喜欢那个，更会爱死这个
Quit screwing around.
别闹了
Second squad，what's your status？
第二队，情况如何？
Uh，we just finished our sweep。Nobody's home.
我们刚检查完，没有人
- Roger。- Sir，this place is dead.
- 知道了 - 长官，这是死城
Whatever happened here，I think we missed it.
不管发生什么事，我们都错过
All right。The area's secured。Let's go in and see what their computer can tell us.
这地方安全，去看看电脑，有什么好看的？
- Wait a minute。It's not secure。- The area's secured，Ripley.
- 等一下，还不安全 - 安全了，蕾普莉
First team，head for operations.
第一队，向主控室前进
- Hudson，see if you can get their C.P.U。on line。- Affirmative.
- 哈德森，接上他们的CUP - 遵命
- Hicks，meet me at the south lock。We're coming in。- Roger.
- 希克斯，在南门等我，我来了 - 收到
He's comin' in。I feel safer already.
他要进来，我觉得好安全
Pendejo jerk-off.
别来烦我
Sir，we got the C.P.U。on line。No problem.
我们已经和GCU连线了，没有问题
Good。Stand by in Operations.
准备行动
Okay，let's go.
我们走吧
Are you all right？
你没事吧？
Yes.
我没事
Sir，they sealed off this wing at both ends，
长官，他们封锁区域的两端
welded the doors and blocked off the stairs with heavy equipment.
舱门封住，楼梯被重物塞着
Mm-hmm。But it looks like the barricade didn't hold.
看起来阻碍物好像没作用
- Any bodies？- No，sir.
- 有尸体吗？- 没有，长官
Last stand.
最后一站
Must have been a hell ofa fight.
看来打过一场大战
Yeah，looks that way.
是啊，好像是
All right，Drake，this way.
好了，垂克，这边
We should be able to cut through the medlab to Operations.
也许能从化验室到主控室
Lieutenant.
中尉
Gorman.
戈曼
Are those the same ones that-
跟你说的一样吗？
Careful，Burke.
小心点，巴克
Looks like love at first sight to me.
看来它对你一见钟情
Oh，he likes you，Burke.
它喜欢你，巴克
Two are alive。The rest are dead.
两个还活着，其余死了
「Surgically removed before embryo implantation.
「进行割除异体胚胎时
Subject Marachek，John J.，died during the procedure.「
约翰死于手术中「
They killed him taking it off.
他们杀了他，取走异形
Yo，Hicks.
希克斯
I think we got something here.
我看有动静了
- Behind us。- One of us？
- 在我们后面 - 我们的人吗？
Apone，where are your people？Anybody in 「D」 block？
阿朋，你的人都在吗？有人在D区吗？
Ah，that's a negative。We're all in Operations.
没有，我们都在主控室
Talk to me，Frosty.
快回答，法斯
Let's keep moving，baby.
继续走
- It's moving。- Which way？
- 在动了 - 哪里？
It's coming straight for us。Straight up.
朝着我们来 一直来
- Fuck！- Hold up.
- 可恶 - 慢点
Ripley.
蕾普莉
Hey。Shh。It's all right.
没事了
- It's all right。- Come on。Just grab her，Corporal.
- 没事了 - 捉住她，下士
Don't be afraid。Come on。We won't hurt you.
别怕，过来，我们不会害你
Shh。It's all right。It's okay.
没有关系
Come on out。Come on.
出来！出来！
- Easy。Easy。- I got her.
- 慢慢来 - 我捉到了
Ow！Damn！
可恶
- Watch her！- She's under the grille！Don't let her go.
- 别跟丢了！- 她在管子下面，别让她跑了
- Frost，get your light up here。- Where'd she go？
- 把灯照过来 - 她跑到哪里？
- Shine the light。- Here。Here.
- 开灯！- 这里！这里！
Here。Here。There she is.
这里！这里！她在这里！
Keep back。Keep back。Don't scare her.
退后！退后！别吓到她！
- Grab her，man。We're gonna lose her。- Damn it！
- 捉住她，她会跑掉 - 可恶！
Kick it out！
加油！
Wait.
等等！
It's okay。It's all right.
好了！没事了！
Don't be afraid.
别害怕
See？
看！
Wait。No，you don't.
等等！不！不可以！
- It's okay。- You're gonna be all right now.
- 没事的 - 你会没事的
Shh.
嘘
Easy。Easy。It's gonna be okay.
慢点！慢点！你会没事的！
It's all right。You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的
Shh，shh，shh，shh，shh.
嘘！嘘！嘘！
Easy。Easy.
慢点！慢点！
- What's her name again？- Rebecca.
- 她叫什么名字？- 丽贝卡
Now think，Rebecca。Concentrate.
回想一下，丽贝卡，专心想
Just start at the beginning.
从头开始想
Where are your parents？
你父母在哪里？
Now，look，Rebecca，you have to try and help-
听着，丽贝卡，你必须…
Gorman，give it a rest，why don't you？
戈曼，让她休息吧
Total brain lock.
头壳坏掉了
Physically，she's okay.
她的身体很好
Borderline malnutrition，but I don't think there's any permanent damage.
只是营养不良，不会有大碍
Come on。We're wasting our time.
走吧，我们在浪费时间
Try this.
喝这个
It's a little hot chocolate.
热巧克力
There you go.
喝吧
Whoop.
喔
That good，huh？
不错吧？
Uh-oh。I made a clean spot here.
我帮你擦一下
Now I've done it。Guess l'll have to do the whole thing.
好了，看来我得擦干净
Hard to believe there's a little girl under all this.
很难想像这里还有个小女孩
And a pretty one too.
而且很漂亮
You don't talk much，do you？
你不喜欢讲话，对吧？
Smoking or nonsmoking？
吸烟区，还是非吸烟区？
Just tell me what you're scanning for，Private.
告诉我你在扫瞄什么？
- P.D.T.s。- What？
- PDTS - 什么东西？
Personal data transmitters.
私人资料转换器
Every colonist had one surgically implanted.
每个移民都有植入
If they're within 20 klicks，we'll read it out here.
二十公里内可以测到
So far，zippo.
但目前为止，什么都没有
I don't know how you managed to stay alive，
我不知道你怎么活下来
but you're one brave kid，Rebecca.
不过你很勇敢，丽贝卡
N-Newt.
纽伊特
- What'd you say？- Newt.
- 你说什么？- 纽伊特
My name's Newt.
我叫纽伊特
Nobody calls me Rebecca except my brother.
除了我哥哥，没人叫我丽贝卡
Newt？I like that.
纽伊特，好名字
I'm Ripley。It's nice to meet you.
我是蕾普莉，很高兴认识你
And who is this，hmm？
这是谁？
- Casey。- Hello，Casey.
- 凯西 - 哈罗，凯西
What about your brother？What's his name？
你哥哥呢？他叫什么？
Timmy.
蒂米
Is Timmy around here too？Maybe hiding like you were？
蒂米也在吗？也许跟你一样藏起来
Any sisters？
你还有姐妹吗？
Mom and dad？
爸妈呢？
Newt，look at me。Where are they？
纽伊特，看着我，他们在哪里？
They're dead，all right？Can I go now？
他们死了，我可以走吗？
I'm sorry，Newt.
很遗憾，纽伊特
Don't you think you'd be safer here with us？
你和我们在一起比较安全
These people are here to protect you.
那些人会保护你
They're soldiers.
他们是军人
It won't make any difference.
那也没有用
Need anything else？
还要什么吗？
Hello，Bishop。Do you need anything else？
主教，你还要什么？
No.
不要
That's a nice pet you got there，Bishop.
你的宠物很可爱，主教
Magnificent，isn't it？
很棒，是不是？
Yo！Stop your grinnin' and drop your linen！Found 'em.
别管别的事，我找到了
- They alive？- Unknown，
- 还活着吗？- 不知道
but it looks like all of them.
看来到处都是
Over at the processing station，Sublevel 3，
它们在加工厂，地下三楼
under the main cooling towers.
主冷冻库也有
Looks like a goddamn town meeting.
看来它们在那里集合
Let's saddle up，Apone.
整装出发，阿朋
Aye，sir.
是，长官
All right。Let's go，people。They ain't payin' us by the hour.
出发了，军机不得延误
Let's go。Head 'em out！
咱们大干一场！
Okay，Frost，you're driving.
好，法斯，你开车
It's okay。Don't worry。It'll be okay.
没事的，别担心 一切都没事
I want a straight 「V」 deployment，second team on left flank.
镇暴队形，第二队左翼
Advance on axial 664。Tracker on line.
方位664前进，镜头打开
Set the 「V」 gain to filter R.F。ambient.
队形前进包围RF
Hudson，tracker on line。Left and right，little buddy.
哈德森，打开镜头，左，右，各位
Forty meters in，bearing 221 ，there should be a stairwell.
四十米，方位221，应该有楼梯
Check。Got it.
有
You want Sublevel 3.
目的地，地下三楼
Let's go，people。Hudson，you got the point.
快点，各位，哈德森，你开路
Hicks，watch our tails.
希克斯，你殿后
Nice and easy。Check those corners.
慢慢来，检查角落
Check those corners.
检查角落
- Watch your spacing。- All right。You heard the man.
- 保持距离 - 听到没有
Don't bunch up。Stay loose.
别乱走
Uh，your transmission's showing a lot ofbreakup.
摄影机有点视讯不良
Probably getting some interference from the structure.
可能受到建筑物干扰
Use those lights.
用灯照
Next one down，and proceed on a 216.
另一个来了，向216区前进
Uh，roger。That's a 216.
知道了，216区
I'm not making that out too well。What is it，Hudson？
看不到是什么东西
You tell me，man。I only work here.
你说呢？我只负责砍怪
What is that？
那是什么？
I don't know.
不知道
Proceed inside.
前进
Watch your fire and check your targets.
看到敌人再打
Remember we're looking for civvies in here.
别忘了我们在找移民
Easy.
别紧张
Tighten it up，Frost。We're getting a little thin.
跟紧点，法斯，你快脱队了
Nice and easy.
慢慢来
Looks like some sort of secreted resin.
看起来像是树脂分泌物
Yeah，but secreted from what？
没错，从哪儿来的？
Nobody touch nothing.
什么都别碰
Busy little creatures，huh？
这怪物还真有一套
Hot as hell in here.
这里真的很热
Yeah，man，but it's a dry heat.
对，不过这是闷热
Knock it off，Hudson.
别闹了，哈德森
Lieutenant，what do those pulse rifles fire？
中尉，这些电波枪火力如何？
Ten millimeter explosive-tip caseless.
10公分口径高爆弹
Standard light armor-piercing round.
标准化轻武器
- Why？- Well，look where your team is.
- 怎么了？- 看看你的队员所在地
They're right under the primary heat exchangers.
在主电源室下面
So？
又怎样？
So if they fire their weapons in there，won't they rupture the cooling system？
他们发射火力会波及冷却系统
- Ho，ho，ho。Yeah。She's absolutely right。- So？So what？
- 她说的一点都没错 - 又怎样？
Look。This whole station is basically a big fusion reactor.
基地理论上是座核子反应炉
Right？
对吗？
So you're talking about a thermonuclear explosion，and adios，muchachos.
她说的是热核子爆炸，一开火就完了
Oh，great。Wonderful.
很好，太棒了
Shit！
见鬼！
Look。Uh… Apone.
听着，阿朋
Look。We can't have any firing in there.
你们不能在里头开枪
I，uh，I want you to collect magazines from everybody.
我命令你把所有弹匣收起来
- Is he fuckin' crazy？- What the hell are we supposed to use，man，harsh language？
- 你疯啦？- 我们要用什么，用粗话骂？
- Flame units only。I want rifles slung。- Sir，I-
- 只准用喷火枪，不准用机枪 - 长官，我…
Just do it，Sergeant。And no grenades.
快点，手榴弹也不行
All right，sweethearts。You heard the man。Pull 'em out。Come on。Let's have 'em.
好了，你们听到了，拿出来
Come on，Vasquez。Clear and lock.
来，娃丝佳，快点
Damn！
可恶！
You too。Give it up，Ski。Come on。Let's go.
你也一样，威伯斯基，拿来
Crowe，I want it now。Give it up.
克罗，我现在就要，拿来
Right on，Vas.
干得好，娃丝佳
Let's go，marine。Give it up.
陆战队员，全都拿来
Frost，you got the duty。Open that bag.
法斯，你负责，打开袋子
- Thanks a lot，Sarge。- Hicks，cover our ass.
- 多谢了，士官长 - 希克斯，掩护我后面
Head 'em out，people.
向前走
I like to keep this handy… for close encounters.
我要这个作埋身肉博
I heard that.
我听到了
Any movement？
有动静吗？
Nothing。Zip.
什么都没有
Holy shit.
老天爷
Newt，go sit up front.
纽伊特，坐到前面
Go on！Now！
去啊，快点！
Steady，people。Let's finish our sweep.
慢慢来，我们要完成行动
We're still marines，and we got a job to do.
我们陆战队要开工了
- Keep it moving。- Easy.
- 继续行动 - 小心点
- Help！- What？
- 救命啊 - 什么事？
- Top，get over here。We got a live one！- You're gonna be all right.
- 那边有个活的 - 你不会有事的
Please… k-kill me.
拜托，杀了我吧
Just stay calm。We're gonna get you outta here.
冷静点，我会救你的
It's gonna be all right。Give me a hand。We gotta get her outta here.
你不会有事，帮我一下，我们得救她出来
- What is it，Dietrich？- Convulsion！
- 怎么回事？迪特里希 - 她抽筋了！
Dietrich，get back！
迪特里希，退后！
Get back！
退后！
- No！- Frost，flamethrower。Kill it！
- 不！- 法斯，发射喷火枪，杀了它！
- Get back！- Flamethrower！Move！
- 退后 - 发射喷火枪，快！
Movement！
有动静了！
- What's the position？- I can't lock in！
- 哪个方向？- 我无法锁定！
Talk to me，Hudson！
怎么样？哈德森
Multiple signals.
讯号繁复
They're closing.
它们接近中
Go to infrared，people。Look sharp！
用红外线镜，小心点！
What's happening，Apone？Can't see anything in here.
怎么回事？什么也看不见
Pull your team out，Gorman.
把部队撤回来，戈曼
I got signals。I got readings in front and behind.
有讯号了，前面，后面
Where，man？I don't see shit.
哪里？我怎么看不到
He's right。There's nothing back here.
他说的对，这里没有东西
Look，I'm telling you。There's something moving，and it ain't us！
是真的，有东西，不是我们！
- Oh，shit。- Tracker's off scale，man.
- 他妈的 - 已经超出追踪器的容量了
They're all around us，man！Jesus！
到处都是，天哪！
Maybe they don't show up on infrared at all.
可能用红外线看不到
Frost！
法斯！
Come on！
走吧！
Jesus Christ，Apone！What is going on？
老天，阿朋，发生什么事？
Wierzbowski and Crowe are down！
威伯斯基和克罗受伤！
- Dietrich，Crowe！- Sound off！Frost！Dietrich，Frost
- 迪特里希，克罗 - 关掉声音！法斯！迪特里希！法斯！
Frost！
法斯！
Wierzbowski？
威伯斯基？
Let's rock！
来吧！
Who's firing？Goddamn it！
谁在开火？该死！
- I ordered to hold fire。- They're coming out of the walls！
- 我命令停火 - 它们从墙上钻出来！
They're coming out of the goddamn walls！Let's book！
它们从墙上钻出来！完蛋了！
- On the right，man。- Uh，Apone，
- 注意右边 - 阿朋
I want you to lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators-
我要你们停火
Vasquez，Drake，hold your fire，goddamn it！
娃丝佳，垂克，停火！该死！
Apone，are you copying me？I want you to lay down suppressing fire…
阿朋，听到没有？停火…
with the incinerators and fall back by squads to the A.P.C.
离开焚化炉
Over。Say again，all after 「incinerator.」
重覆，全部退到焚化炉后
I said I want you to lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators and fall back…
我要你们停火，退到…
by squads to the A.P.C。Over.
焚化炉后，完毕
Hey！
救命！
- Sarge！Sarge！- Apone.
- 中士！- 阿朋
Talk to me。Apone？Copy！Copy！
快说话，阿朋，收到！收到！
- Talk to me，Apone。- He's gone！
- 快说话，阿朋 - 他死了
- Get them out of there！- Shut up！
- 叫他们回来 - 住嘴
- Do it now！Hicks，whoever's left，get - Shut up！
- 快点，活着的人全都撤退 - 闭嘴！
Just shut up！Goddamn it！
住嘴！该死的！
It's coming out of the goddamn walls！Where's Apone？Where's Apone？
它们从墙上钻出来！阿朋在哪儿？
The sarge is gone！Let's get the fuck out of here！
士官长死了，我们赶快走！
- Let's move it！- Let's go，marine！
- 快走！- 快走！
Hudson？Vasquez？
哈德森！娃丝佳？
Hudson，look out！Get it！
哈德森！小心！打死它！
Watch it！
小心！
- Hicks。- Come on。Behind you！Fall back！
- 希克斯 - 在你身后，撤退！
- I told them to fall back。- Fall back，goddamn it，now！
- 我叫他们撤退 - 撤退！妈的！立刻！
- They're cut off！- Hudson，move your ass！
- 他们被切断！- 哈德森！快跑路！
- Do something！- Let's go，marine！
- 想想办法！- 撤退！陆战队！
Fuck！
可恶！
- Come on。Keep moving，baby。- Hold on，Newt.
- 快撤退！- 坐好！纽伊特！
Ripley，what the hell are you doing？
蕾普莉！你在干什么？
Turn around！
给我回去！
That's an order！
这是命令！
- Get off me，damn it！- Goddamn it，that's an order！
- 妈的！别碰我！- 见鬼，这是命令！
You had your chance，Gorman.
你没机会了
Come on！
快点！
Come on。Let's move it！
快点！走！
Come on！Let's go！Let's go！
快点！走！快走！
It's blocked，man。We gotta go around！
此路不通，我们得绕道！
- Open the door！Hicks！- Drake，we are leaving！
- 去开门，希克斯 - 垂克，我们要走了！
Get them，man！
这些王八蛋！
Run for it！
快上车！
Shit！
该死！
- Go！Go！- Come on，man！Come on！
- 快走吧！- 加把劲！加把劲！
Drake，come on！
垂克！快来呀！
No！
不！
- Fire in the hole！- He's gone！
- 车上起火 - 他没救了！
Put it out！Put it out！Go！Go！
快去灭火
- Come on。Put it out！- Drake's coming，man！
- 快去灭火！- 垂克 快来！
- He's gone！- Drake！No，he's not！
- 他没救了！- 垂克！不！他没有…！
Forget him！He's gone！
算了！他死了！
They're in the goddamn door！
快关门！
Eat this！
吃子弹吧！
Ripley！
蕾普莉！
Go，go，go！
走！走！走！
It's all right！We're clear！
没事了！我们脱身了！
Ripley，you've blown the transaxle！
蕾普莉，你弄坏了轮胎！
You're just grinding metal！
现在就个金属轮子在滚！
Come on，ease down.
放慢！放慢！
Ease down.
放慢！
Ease down。Ease down。Ease down.
放慢！放慢！放慢！
You okay？
你还好吗？
l'm all right。Hudson.
我很好
Get away from me，man！
不要你管
Lieutenant。What happened to Gorman？
中尉，戈曼如何？
I don't know。Maybe a concussion.
不知道，也许撞到了
- But he's alive。- He's dead！
- 还活着 - 他死定了！
Wake up，pendejo，and then I'm gonna kill you！
醒醒，我要宰了你！
Back off。Right now.
退后！快点！
Fuck！Somebody get me a first aid kit.
给我急救箱
Hey。Hey，look.
嘿，看
The sarge and Dietrich aren't dead，man.
士官长和迪特里希没死
Their signs are real low，but they ain't dead.
讯号很弱，不过还没死
- Then we go back in there and get them。- Fuck that！
- 我们回去救人 - 去你的！
- We don't leave our people behind - I ain't going back in there.
- 我们不会留下战友 - 我才不回去
You can't help them！
你们也没办法！
You can't。Right now they're being cocooned just like the others.
没有救了，他们会像其他人一样变成卵状
- Oh，dear Lord Jesus，this ain't happenin'，man。- Damn it.
- 老天，不会吧 - 见鬼
This can't be happenin'，man。This isn't happenin'！
不可能！不可能！
All right。We got seven canisters of CN-20.
我们有七支CN20散弹炮
I say we roll them in there and nerve gas the whole fucking nest.
我们用摧泪弹打它们
That's worth a try，but we don't even know if it's gonna affect them.
值得一试，不过根本不知道有没有效
- Let's just bug out and call it even。Okay？- What are we talking about this for？
- 我们走吧，算平手好了 - 还说这些干嘛？
I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit.
最好从空中用核弹炸掉这地方
It's the only way to be sure.
这是唯一的方法
- Fuckin' 「A」！- Hold on。Hold on one second.
- 真有一套 - 慢点！慢点！
This installation has a substantial dollar value attached to it.
这是很有价值的巨资工程
They can bill me.
叫公司寄帐单给我
Okay，look。This is an emotional moment for all of us，okay？
慢点，大家都很激动
I know that。But let's not make snap judgments，please.
这我知道，但我们不要开玩笑，拜托
This is clearly-clearly an important species we're dealing with，
我们面对的是很重要的生物
and I don't think that you or I or anybody has the right…
我不认为你们有权…
- to arbitrarily exterminate them。- Wrong.
- 任意杀光它 - 错了
Yeah。Watch us.
你等着瞧吧
Maybe you haven't been keeping up on current events，
也许你瞎了
but we just got our asses kicked，pal！
我们差点没命！
Look。I'm not blind to what's going on，
我不是瞎子
but I cannot authorize that kind of action.
我不同意这行动
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Well，I believe Corporal Hicks…
我相信希克斯下士…
has authority here.
有指挥权
Corporal Hicks is-
希克斯下士
This operation is under military jurisdiction，
这是项军事行动
and Hicks is next in chain of command.
希克斯有第二指挥权
Am I right，Corporal？
对吗？下士
Yeah.
对
Yeah，that's right.
对，没错
Yeah。Look，Ripley。Yes.
听着，蕾普莉
This is a multimillion-dollar installation，okay？
这是很昂贵的工程
He can't make that kind of decision.
他不能乱下命令
He's just a grunt。Uh，no offense.
他只是小兵，别介意
- None taken。Ferro，do you copy？- Standing by.
- 没关系，弗洛，你听到吗？- 准备好了
Prep for dust off。We're gonna need immediate evac.
我们马上撤退
Roger。On our way.
收到，立即出发
I say we take off，nuke the site from orbit。It's the only way to be sure.
我说起飞后用核弹炸掉这地方，这是唯一的方法
Let's do it.
出发了
Let's go。Pick it up，Hudson。Pick it up，baby.
快点，抬起来，哈德森，抬起来
All right。Set him down here.
好了，把他放下来
Move it，Spunkmeyer。We're rolling.
快点，史巴梅尔，起飞了
Hold on a second。There's something-
慢点，有东西…
Just get up here.
少罗唆，快上来
I'm in。Ramp closing.
我进来了，挡板关起来
Spunkmeyer.
史巴梅尔
Goddamn it.
该死
Well，where the fuck-
你去哪儿了？
Run！
快跑！
Well，that's great。That's just fuckin' great，man.
完了，这下全完了
Now what the fuck are we supposed to do？
现在该怎么办？
We're in some real pretty shit now，man！
我们现在可惨了！
Are you finished？
你好了没有？
You all right？
你还好吗？
I guess we're not gonna be leaving now，right？
现在没办法走了，对不对？
I'm sorry，Newt.
抱歉，纽伊特
You don't have to be sorry。It wasn't your fault。That's it，man.
你不必道歉，这不是你的错
Game over，man！Game over！
完了，什么都完了！
What the fuck are we gonna do now？What are we gonna do？
我们该怎么办？怎么办？
Maybe we could build a fire。Sing a couple of songs，huh？Why don't we try that？
我们可以生个火，唱唱歌，这样好不好？
We'd better get back 'cause it'll be dark soon，
天黑前得回去
and they mostly come at night，mostly.
它们都在夜间活动，多半都是
That's everything，right？All right。This is absolutely everything…
全都在这儿吗？好的，这些都是…
that we could salvage out of the A.P.C。wreckage.
失事船上能用的武器
We got four pulse rifles with about 50 rounds each.
四把50连发电波散弹枪
That ain't so good.
并不太理想
We got，uh，15 of these M-40 grenades.
还有15个M40手榴弹
Don't touch that.
别碰
- Dangerous，honey。- Is that the only flamethrower？
- 危险，甜心 - 那是唯一的喷火枪吗？
Yeah。It's only half full，but it's functional.
对，燃料只剩一半，还能用
Got another one，it's damaged-I don't know about that one.
另一个坏了，我不大清楚这支
But the good news-we got four of these robot sentries，
好消息是我们有四套这种机械感应器
with display and scanners intact.
而且大致都相当完好
They really kick ass。I think they'll come in handy.
如果我们要消灭异形的话，这些应该派得上用场
How long after we're declared overdue can we expect a rescue？
没按时回航，几时才有救援？
Seventeen days.
17天
Seventeen days？
17天？
Hey，man，I don't wanna rain on your parade，but we're not gonna last 17 hours.
老兄，我不想扫兴，我们连17小时都撑不了
Those things are gonna come in here like they did before。They're gonna come in here-
那怪物不会放过我们，他们会…
- Hudson！Hudson！- They're gonna come in here and they're gonna get us！
- 哈德森！哈德森！- 他们会追过来把我们都干掉！
This little girl survived longer than that…
这小女孩没有武器…
with no weapons and no training.
没受过军事训练，都活到现在
Right？
对吧？
Why don't you put her in charge？
让她指挥呀
You'd better just start dealing with it，Hudson。Listen to me.
你最好要振作点，哈德森，听我说
Hudson，just deal with it because we need you.
哈德森，我们需要你
And I'm sick of your bullshit.
别罗唆
Now，I want you to get on a terminal and call up some kind of floor plan file.
用电脑找出楼层平面图
Do you understand？Construction blueprints。I don't care.
懂吗？建筑蓝图
Anything that shows the layout of this place。Are you listening？
这地方的布局平面图，你在听吗？
- Yeah。- I need to see air ducts.
- 有 - 我要通风口
I need to see electrical access tunnels，subbasements，
小通道，地下室
every possible way into this complex.
任何能逃出这里的资料
- We don't have much time。- Okay.
- 时间不多 - 好
- Okay，I'm on it。- Hudson！
- 好，我去找 - 哈德森！
Just relax.
放轻松
I'll be in medlab。I'll check on Gorman，continue my analysis.
我到化验室看戈曼，继续研究
Fine。You do that.
很好，这样最好
So this service tunnel must be how they're moving back and forth.
它一定是走这条通道
That's right。It moves from the processing station…
没错，它们从处理室…
right into the sublevel here.
走到地下室
Come down on that。Okay，come over.
下来一点，好，再过来
Hold。Go back。Okay，punch that in right there.
回去，好，定点就是这里
- No。It's back here。- Okay.
- 不，回去 - 好的
Well，there's a pressure door at this end.
这里有个压力舱
Couldn't we put one of the remote sentry units in the tunnel and then seal that door？
把它关闭可以阻挡一阵子
Yeah，that'll work，but we gotta figure on them getting into the complex.
的确有用，但它们可能从别处进来
That's right，so we repair the barricades at these two intersections.
没错，所以我们要在这些交叉点放置阻碍物
Right。And weld plate steel over these ducts…
对，再把通道封死…
here and here and here.
这里和这里
That way they can only come at us from these two corridors.
这样他们就只能通过2条走廊过来
All right。Then we put the other sentry units here and here，right？
阻止它到化验室及主控室
- Right。- Outstanding.
- 好了 - 了不起
Now all we need is a deck of cards.
现在可以放心玩牌了
All right，people。Let's move like we got a purpose.
好了，大伙，照计划进行
- Affirmative。- Affirmative.
- 遵命！- 遵命！
Do your thing，baby。Come on，Vasquez。Let's get the hell outta here.
我们封闭这通道，宝贝，快点，搞完走人
Hudson here。「A」 and 「B」 sentries are in place and keyed.
我是哈德森，A和B感应器已经全部装好了
- Roger。Stand by。Arming now。- Test it，Hudson.
- 待命，我们已经在准备武装了 - 可以了，哈德森
Do it！Fire in the hole！
动手！开火！
Okay，great。Let's get the hell outta here！
我们赶快离开这里吧！
We're sealing the tunnel。Come on，baby.
我们要封锁这个区域，快点
For what it's worth.
快点，希望有用
Here。I want you to put this on.
我要你戴上这个
- What's it for？- It's a locator.
- 做什么？- 定位器
Then I can find you anywhere in the complex on this.
可以在任何地方找到你
- It's just a precaution。- Thanks.
- 只是为安全起见 - 谢了
Doesn't mean we're engaged or anything.
这不表示我们订婚了
All right，what's next？
下一步是什么？
Last stop.
到了
Get in.
上床
Scoot down。That's good.
脚放进去，这才乖
Now，you lie here and have a nap。You're very tired.
在这儿睡一下，你累坏了
I don't want to。I have scary dreams.
我不睡，我会做恶梦
Well，I bet Casey doesn't have scary dreams.
我打赌凯西不会做恶梦
Let's take a look.
看一看
Nope。Nothing bad in there.
没有，没有什么
See？Maybe you could just try to be like her，hmm？
看，你可以跟她一样
Ripley，she doesn't have bad dreams…
蕾普莉，她是不会做恶梦的…
because she's just a piece of plastic.
因为她只是布偶
Right。I'm sorry，Newt.
对，抱歉，纽伊特
There.
对着你
My mommy always said there were no monsters…
我妈常说这里没有怪物
no real ones-but there are.
没有真的怪物，可是真的有
Yes，there are，aren't there？
真的有
Why do they tell little kids that？
他们为什么这么说？
Most of the time it's true.
多数时候他们都是对的
Did one of those things grow inside her？
她会不会被怪兽攻击？
I don't know，Newt.
我不知道
That's the truth.
真的
Isn't that how babies come？I mean，people babies？
人类的小孩，不就是这样来的吗？
- They grow inside you。- Oh，that's very different.
- 也是体内孕育的 - 不，两者有很大的不同
Did you ever have a baby？
你有没有生过小孩？
Yes，I did。I had a little girl.
有，我有一个小女儿
- Where is she？- She's gone.
- 她现在在哪里？- 她走了
You mean dead.
你是说她死了？
Here.
这给你
Take this.
来，戴上它
For luck.
保平安用
There's that.
好了
Don't go，please.
别走！拜托！
Newt，I'm gonna be right in the next room.
我就在隔壁
And you see that camera right up there？
看到墙上的电眼吗？
I can see you right through that camera，
我从那里随时看到
all the time to see if you're safe.
你是不是安全
I'm not gonna leave you，Newt.
我不会离开你，纽伊特
I mean that。That's a promise.
真的，我保证
You promise？
你保证？
I cross my heart.
我发誓
- And hope to die？- And hope to die.
- 死都不会？- 死都不会
Now go to sleep，and don't dream.
睡吧，不要做梦
Sneak.
小鬼
The molecular acid oxidizes after the creature's death，completely neutralizing it.
怪物死后酸血层氧化就没危险
Bishop，you know，that's very interesting，but it doesn't really get us anywhere，does it？
主教，很有意思，不过我没兴趣
I'm trying to figure out what we're dealing with here.
我们到底在对抗什么东西？
Let's go through it again.
重新想想
They grab the colonists，they move them over there…
它们捉住移民，送到这里…
and they immobilize them to be hosts for more of these.
作为宿主，再繁殖更多怪物
Which would mean that there would have to be a lot of these parasites，right？
这表示有更多异形，对吗？
One for each colonist。That's over 100，at least.
就算一个宿主对应一个异形，至少超过一百只
Yes。That follows.
是的，没错
But each one of these things comes from an egg，right？
每个异形都是卵生的
So who's laying these eggs？
谁把蛋藏起来呢？
I'm not sure.
我不确定
It must be something we haven't seen yet.
一定是我们还没见过的东西
Hey，maybe it's like an ant hive.
也许就像蚂蚁窝
Bees，man。Bees have hives.
你是说蜂窝吧？
You know what I mean。There's，like，one female that runs the whole show.
你知道我的意思，它就像是女王蜂一样掌控全局
- Yes，the queen。- Ueah，the mama.
- 没错，就是女王蜂 - 没错，就是它
She's badass，man。I mean，big.
它很难缠
These things ain't ants，estupido。I know that.
这些东西可不像蚂蚁，我知道
Bishop，I want these specimens destroyed as soon as you're finished with them.
主教，我要你把标本销毁
- Is that clear？- Mr。Burke gave instructions…
- 懂吗？- 巴克先生下达指令…
that they were to be kept alive in stasis for return to the company labs.
叫我带活标本回基地
He was very specific about it.
他特别交待的
Look。Those two specimens are worth millions to the bio-weapons division，right？
这些标本价值非凡
Now，if you're smart，we can both come out of this heroes，
如果你够聪明，咱们会成为英雄
and we will be set up for life.
下半辈子都不愁吃穿
You're crazy，Burke。Do you know that？
你疯了，巴克，你知道吗？
Do you really think you can get a dangerous organism like that past I.C.C。quarantine？
这种危险生物能通过检疫吗？
How can they impound it if they don't know about it？
没人了解它们，怎么通不过？
But they will know about it，Burke，from me.
我会告诉他们
Just like they'll know that you were responsible for the deaths of 157 colonists.
他们也会知道，你害死157个移民
- Wait a second。- You sent them to that ship.
- 等一下 - 你派他们来这里
- You're wrong。- I just checked the colony log.
- 你弄错了 - 我查过移民日志
Directive dated 6-12-79，signed Burke，Carter J.
出发日期61279，巴克卡特签署
You sent them out there，and you didn't even warn them.
你派他们来，却没警告他们
- Why didn't you warn them，Burke？- Okay，look.
- 你为何不警告他们？- 听着
What if that ship didn't even exist？Do you ever think about that？
你想过那鬼船也许不存在吗？
I didn't know。So now if I went and made a major security situation out of it，
我并不知道，要是我小题大做
everybody steps in，administration steps in，and there's no exclusive rights for anybody.
每个单位都来干涉，公司得不到专利权
Nobody wins。So I made a decision，and it was wrong.
大家都吃亏，我犯了错
It was a bad call，Ripley。It was a bad call.
我只是判断错误，蕾普莉
- Bad call？- Right.
- 判断错误？- 没错
These people are dead，Burke！
那些人都死了！
Don't you have any idea what you've done here？
你知道你干了什么吗？
I'm gonna make sure that they nail you right to the wall for this！
我一定要让他们逮到你送进监狱！
You're not gonna sleaze your way out of this one.
别想夹着尾巴跑掉
Right to the wall.
我要整垮你
Ripley。I-
蕾普莉
You know，I expected more from you.
我本来对你很有信心
I thought you'd be smarter than this.
我以为你是聪明人
Well，I'm happy to disappoint you.
我很高兴让你失望
- What is it？What's going on？- They're coming.
- 怎么回事？- 它们来了
- Where？- In the tunnel.
- 在哪里？- 在隧道里
Here we go。「A」 and 「B」 gun tracking far end。Multiple targets.
我们的武器已经追踪到它们并开火，目标有好多个
Those ammo counters go.
这些武器还真行
「B」 gun's down 50%…
B枪弹药已经用掉一半了…
Man，it's a shooting gallery down there.
下面一定战况激烈
Sixty rounds left on 「B.」
B枪只剩下60发子弹了
Forty。Twenty。Ten.
40发、20发、10发！
「B」 gun's dry。Twenty on 「A.」
B枪弹药已经用完了，A枪只剩下20发
Ten。Five.
10发、5发！
That's it.
用完了
Jesus，they were wall-to-wall in there.
老天啊，下面真是一场混战
They're at the pressure door.
它们在撞门
Man，listen to that.
我的天啊
Bishop here。I'm afraid I have some bad news.
我是主教，有坏消息
Well，that's a switch.
这倒新鲜
It's very pretty，Bishop，but what are we looking for？
很漂亮，主教，有什么问题？
That's it。Emergency venting.
就是那个紧急通风口
Oh，that's beautiful，man。Oh，man，that-that just beats it all.
真好，真是智者千虑必有一失
- How long till it blows？- Four hours.
- 多久喷一次？- 4小时
With a blast radius of 30 kilometers，
范围大概30公里半径
equal to about 40 megatons.
平均4千万吨
- We got problems。- I don't believe this。I don't fucking believe this.
- 难题来了 - 我不敢相信
Vasquez，close the shutters.
娃丝佳，把窗闸关起来
Why can't we shut it down from here？
为什么不从这里关闭？
I'm sorry。The crash caused too much damage.
抱歉，坠机造成严重损害
An overload is inevitable at this point.
没有办法修复
Oh，man，and I was getting short.
天，越来越没希望
Four more weeks and out。Now l'm gonna buy it on this rock.
只差4星期我便可以退役，我们被困死了
- It ain't half fair，man。- Hudson，give us a break！
- 不公平 - 哈德森，少罗唆！
Four more weeks。Oh，man.
四个礼拜，天啊
We've got to get the other drop ship from the Sulaco.
我们必须派一艘船来救我们
I mean，there must be some way of bringing it down on remote.
一定有办法摇控太空船
How？The transmitter was on the A.P.C。It's wasted.
怎么做？联络系统坏了
I don't care how，but we'd better think of something。We'd better think of a way.
不管怎样，我们最好想办法
- Think of what？We're fucked！We're doomed！- Shut up！
- 想个屁，我们死定了 - 住嘴！
Shut up！What about the colony transmitters？
住嘴，殖民地的通讯器呢？
The uplink tower down at the other end。Why can't we use that？
终端在控制塔，我们可以利用吗？
No，I checked。The hardware in between here and there was damaged.
不行，我查过，那里的通道被堵住
We can't align the dish.
没办法联接天线
Well，somebody's gonna have to go out there，
一定得有人出去
take a portable terminal，go out there and patch in manually.
拿电脑亲自去修复
Oh，yeah，sure。With those things running around？You can count me out.
是呀，怪物就在附近徘徊，我可不去
- Guess we can just count you out of everything。- I'll go.
- 你哪儿都不敢去 - 我去
That's right，man。Why don't you go，man？
没错，没错，你去吧
- I'll go。- What？
- 我去 - 什么？
I'll go。I mean，I'm the only one qualified to remote pilot the ship anyway.
我去，只有我有资格遥控太空船
- Yeah，right，man。Bishop should go。- Good idea.
- 应该让主教去 - 好主意
Believe me，I'd prefer not to.
相信我，我宁可不去
I may be synthetic，but I'm not stupid.
虽然我是人造人，我可不笨
How long？
有多远？
This conduit runs almost to the uplink assembly-180 meters.
水管几乎一直通到上层大厅，180公尺
- Say 40 minutes to crawl down there - Right.
- 爬到那儿要40分钟 - 好的
An hour to patch in and align the antenna.
联接天线大约要一个小时
Thirty minutes to prep the ship，
把太空船准备好要30分钟
and about 50 minutes flight time。It's gonna be close.
飞行时间约50分钟，时间紧迫
- Good luck。- See you soon.
- 祝好运 - 回头见
Watch your fingers.
小心
Vaya con Dios，man.
希望他顺利
This is unbelievable。Twenty meters and closing.
真是不敢相信已经逼近至20米处
- Fifteen。- How many？
- 15米处 - 多少只
Can't tell。Lots.
很难说，反正很多
「D」 gun's down 50%…
D枪已经用了一半的子弹…
「C」 gun's right behind it.
C枪也差不多了
Stopping them。It ain't stopping them.
难道没有办法阻止它们吗？
- 150 rounds on 「D.」 - Come on。Come on，baby.
- D枪只剩下150发了 - 挺住啊
Hundred rounds.
100发
Come on！Come on！
加油！加油！
「D」 gun's down to 20.
B枪只剩下20发了
Ten.
10发
Damn it！
见鬼！
Wait！They're retreating.
等等，它们撤退了
The guns stopped them.
我们的枪火阻止它们了
You're right.
你说得对
Next time they walk right up and knock.
下一次就没这么多子弹了
Yeah，but they don't know that.
不过它们不知道这点
They're probably looking for other ways to get in.
它们也许会从别的地方进来
That'll take 'em a while.
我们可以解决它们的
- Maybe we got 'em demoralized。- Shut up！
- 也许它们被我们逼得动弹不得 - 闭嘴
I want you two walking perimeter.
我要你们在四处巡逻
Move！
快去！
Hey，listen.
听着
We're all in strung-out shape，
大家都快累死了
but stay frosty and alert.
可是要沉着机警点
We can't afford to let one of those bastards in here.
那怪物进来我们就完了
All right。Vamonos.
好的
How long's it been since you got any sleep？
你多久没睡？
Twenty-four hours？
24小时？
Hicks，I'm not gonna end up like those others.
希克斯，我不想像他们那样
You'll take care of it，won't you？
你会「处理善后」吧？
If it comes to that，I'll do us both.
如果那怪物进来，我会把我俩先杀了
Listen，let's just make sure it doesn't come to that.
听好，希望不会那样
- All right？- All right.
- 好吗？- 好的
Hey，I want to introduce you to a personal friend of mine.
我跟你介绍一个好朋友
This is an M-41A pulse rifle，10 millimeter，
这是M41A电波机关枪，10厘米口径
with an over-and-under 30 millimeter pump-action grenade launcher.
上下都有30厘米手榴弹筒
Feel the weight.
试试重量
Okay，what do I do？
好吧，我该怎么做？
- Okay，pull it in tight here。- Right.
- 抓紧 - 好
Uh-huh。Lean into it。Mm-hmm.
夹紧
All right。Now，it will kick some.
会有后座力
All right。When the counter reads zero here，you-
当指数变零时
- I press this up？- That's right.
- 按这个？- 对
Get another one in quick。Slap it in hard.
赶快换弹匣，用力卡住
Right。And you're ready to rock and roll.
这样就能大干了
- What's this？- That's the grenade launcher.
- 这是什么？- 手榴弹筒
I don't think you want to mess with that.
最好别碰
You started this。Show me everything.
是你开的头，全教我吧
I can handle myself.
我能自己来
Yeah，I noticed.
我注意到了
How do you feel？
你还好吧？
All right，I guess。One hell of a hangover.
还好吧！好像大醉一场
- Look，Ripley，I just want - Forget it.
- 蕾普莉，我只想… - 算了
Excuse me.
借过
Shh，shh，shh，shh，shh。It's okay。It's okay.
嘘！嘘！嘘！没事了！
（启动）
Newt，wake up.
纽伊特，醒醒！
Wha-Be quiet.
别出声
We're in trouble.
我们遇上麻烦了
No！
不！
Move，Newt！
快走！纽伊特！
Hey！
嘿！
Help！Help！
救命！救命！
- Hicks！- Somebody！
- 希克斯！- 来人！
Say again，Bishop.
主教，再说一次
You've got it into auto-refuel mode，and it's sequencing right？
你接通自动加油的程式，频率没错？
That's right。Okay，good。Stay on it.
好，继续联络
Get back to me when you've activated the launch cycle.
等你发动引擎再联络
- Roger。- He's at the uplink tower.
- 收到 - 他在上层塔台
Good。Terrific.
太棒了
- Hicks！Hicks！Hicks！- Help！
- 希克斯！希克斯！- 救命！
- Help！Help！- Hicks，help us！
- 救命！救命！- 希克斯！救命呀！
- Break the glass！Break it。Break it。- Yes.
- 把玻璃弄破！弄破呀！弄破！- 聪明！
I'll try.
我试试看
Ripley，I'm scared.
蕾普莉，我好怕
Me too.
我也一样
Stay here.
待在这里
It's the medlab。Hudson！
是医疗化验室，哈德森！
Vasquez，meet me in medlab。We got a fire.
娃丝佳，到化验室会合，有火灾
We're on our way.
马上来
They're coming，Newt.
他们来了
Shoot it out！
射玻璃！
- Hudson！- Jesus.
- 哈德森 - 天啊
Christ，kid，look out！
孩子！当心！
Fucking die.
去死吧
- Over there！Ready？- Yeah！Yeah！
- 那边，好了吗？- 好了
Now！
马上！
- Hudson？- Yeah。All clear.
- 哈德森 - 安全了
Nailed the other one。It's history，man.
另一只也死了，完蛋了
Jesus.
天啊
Burke-It was Burke.
是巴克，是巴克搞的鬼
I say we grease this rat-fuck son of a bitch right now.
现在就宰了这混帐
Just doesn't make any goddamn sense.
一点道理也没有
He figured that he could get an alien back through quarantine…
他以为能偷运一只异形，通过检疫站…
if one of us was impregnated…
如果我们之中有人能…孕育它
whatever you call it…
不管你怎么说
and then frozen for the trip home.
然后把尸体冷冻运回去
Nobody would know about the embryos we were carrying…
没人知道我们带着怪物回去
me and Newt.
我和纽伊特
Wait a minute，now。We'd all know.
等等，我们不知道
Yes。The only way he could do it…
他只要…
is if he sabotaged certain freezers on the way home.
在回航途中破坏我们的冷冻库…
Namely yours.
名义上，你们的
Then he could jettison the bodies and make up any story he liked.
然后再把尸体丢掉，随便编什么故事
- Fuck！He's dead。- You're dog meat，pal.
- 他死定了 - 太岂有此理了
This is so nuts.
真是一派胡言
I mean，listen-Listen to what you're saying.
听你在说什么话
It's paranoid delusion.
都是你幻想的
It's really sad。It's pathetic.
真悲哀，真可怜
You know，Burke，I don't know which species is worse.
巴克，我不知道谁比较坏
You don't see them fucking each other over for a goddamn percentage.
它们不会为了利益互相残杀
All right。We waste him。No offense.
好，我们宰了他
No！He's gotta go back-
不，他得回去
- They cut the power。- What do you mean，they cut the power？
- 它们把电力切断了 - 什么？它们切断电源？
How could they cut the power，man？They're animals.
怎么可能？他们是动物
I want you two with trackers，checking the corridors！Move！
你们去查走廊，快点！
- Gorman，watch Burke！- I got him.
- 戈曼，看着巴克 - 交给我
Newt，stay close.
纽伊特，靠紧点
- I'll go this side。- You do that，man.
- 我走这边 - 去吧
- Anything？- There's something.
- 有动静吗？- 那儿
It's inside the complex.
它在里面
You're just reading me.
你测到的是我
No，no，it ain't you.
不！不！不是你！
They're inside-inside the perimeter。They're in here.
它们在里面，它们在这儿
Hudson，stay cool！Vasquez？
哈德森，冷静点，娃丝佳？
Hudson may be right.
哈德森可能说对了
- Get back，both of you！- The signal's weird.
- 你们都回来 - 信号好怪
Must be some interference or something.
一定是某种干扰
There's movement all over the place！
到处都有讯号！
- Get back to Operations。- It's game time.
- 快回主控室 - 游戏开始
Newt.
纽伊特
Seal the door。Hurry！
把门封起来！快点！
Come on！Come on！Come on！Get back！
快！快！回来！
Work fast.
动作快点
Cover your eyes，Newt。Don't look at the light.
把眼睛遮起来，别看火焰
Movement。Signal's clean.
有动静，信号清楚
Range，20 meters.
范围，20米
They found a way in，something we missed.
它们找到进来的路，我们有漏洞
We didn't miss anything.
我们没有漏洞
Eighteen。Seventeen meters.
18米…17米…
Something under the floor，not in the plans。I don't know.
蓝图上没有的，我不知道
- Fifteen meters。- Ripley！
- 15米 - 蕾普莉！
- Definitely inside the barricades。- Let's go.
- 绝对在障碍物内 - 我们走吧
Thirteen meters。That's right outside the door.
13米，就在门外
Hicks，Vasquez，get back！This is a big fucking signal.
你们退后，讯号真大
- How you doing，Vasquez？Talk to me。- Almost there.
- 娃丝佳，你那里如何？快回答 - 快好了
That's it.
好了
Twelve meters。Eleven.
12米、11米
- Ten。- Then they're right on us.
- 10米 - 他们要攻过来了
- Nine meters。- Remember-short，controlled bursts.
- 9米 - 记住，快速开枪
Eight meters.
8米
Seven.
7米
- Six。- It can't be。That's inside the room.
- 6米 - 在里面，不可能
- It's reading right，man。Look！- Well，you're not reading it right.
- 上面这么显示 - 你看错了
- Five meters，man。Four。- What the hell？
- 5米，天啊，4米 - 搞什么鬼？
Oh，my God。Oh，sh-Give me the light.
老天，把灯给我
There they go！Over there！Get them！
它们来了，在那边，干掉它们
Come on！Get them！
快！快！干掉它们！
Do something，Gorman！
快想办法！
Get them！Look out！There's more of them！There's more of them！
干掉它们！还有好多！
Medical！Get to Medical！Do it！Now！
快到医药中心！快点！
Hudson，look out！Look out！
哈德森！小心！小心！
Now！
快！
Burke！
巴克！
Open this door！
把门打开！
Burke！Open it！
巴克！快打开！
Go！Fall back！
走！撤退！
Go！
走！
- Die，motherfucker！- Burke！
- 去死吧！混蛋！- 巴克！
Hudson！Hudson！
哈德森！哈德森！
Motherfucker！Come on！Come on！Come and get it，baby！Come on！
王八蛋！来！快点！过来！
I don't got all day！Come on！Come on！Come on，you bastard！
随时奉陪！来啊！来呀！混帐！
Come on！You too！Oh，you want some of this？
你也一样，还要吗？你也想尝尝？
Fuck you！
去你的！
Fuck you！Hicks！
去你的！希克斯！
Hudson！
哈德森！
Come on。Let's go！
快走！
It's locked！
锁住了！
- Got it！Let's go！Let's go！- Go！Go！
- 好了！走！- 走！走！
- Move，Gorman！- Seal it！
- 戈曼！快点！- 封起来
Burke！Goddamn you！Open this door！
巴克！天杀的！开门！
Get back！
退后！
- Hurry up。- Gorman，get out of the way！
- 快点！- 戈曼！让开！
Ripley，this way！What-
蕾普莉！这里！
Wait。Get behind me.
等一下，走在我后面
Whatever you're gonna do，do it fast！
我不管你要干嘛！快点！
Hicks！Go！Come on。Let's go.
希克斯！走！
Move！
快！
- Which way is it to the landing field from here？- This way.
- 降落场在哪边？- 这边
Go right.
向右
This way。This way.
这边！这边！
- Which way？- Straight ahead and left.
- 哪边？- 往前然后左转
Bishop，do you read me？Come in。Over.
主教，听到吗？请回答
The ship is on its way.
船快到了
E.T.A.，16 minutes.
预定16分钟抵达
Stand by there。We're on our way.
准备好，我们要去了
- Which way now？- That way.
- 现在哪条路？- 那条
- No，wait。This way。- You sure？
- 不，这条 - 你确定吗？
Vasquez，move！
娃丝佳！快来！
- Right up here。It's just up here。- Hicks！
- 就在这上面 - 希克斯
We're almost there.
我们快到了！
Newt，wait！Newt！
纽伊特，等一下！纽伊特！
Vasquez！
娃丝佳！
Go！
走！
Oh，no！
不！
Newt.
纽伊特
Up there。There's a shortcut across the roof.
屋顶有捷径
Hicks.
希克斯
You always were an asshole，Gorman.
戈曼，你老是那么笨
- Newt！God！- Ripley！
- 纽伊特！- 蕾普莉！
Newt！
纽伊特！
Hicks！Hicks，get her！Hurry！
希克斯！快去救她！快！
- Hold on，Newt！- I'm slipping！
- 纽伊特，抓住！- 我要滑下去了！
- Don't let go。- Ripley！
- 别松手！- 蕾普莉！
- Hold on。Gotcha！- Help！
- 抓住了！- 救命！
I gotcha.
我抓住你！
Newt！
纽伊特！
No！
不！
Come on。We can find her with this.
我们用这个找她
- Stay where you are，Newt。- Ripley！
- 待在那儿别动 - 蕾普莉！
We're coming.
我们就到了
Ripley！
蕾普莉！
This way.
这边
- She's close。- Newt！
- 接近了 - 纽伊特！
Ripley！
蕾普莉！
Where are you？Can you hear me？
你在哪儿？听到吗？
Newt！Here！
纽伊特，这边！
- I'm here！- Where？
- 我在这儿 - 哪里
Newt，are you okay？
纽伊特，你还好吗？
We'll have to cut it.
得切断它
Climb down，honey。We've gotta cut through.
趴下，我们得切断它
Newt？
纽伊特？
Now，don't move。Stay very still.
别动，要静静的
Okay.
好
We're almost there。Hang in there，okay？
快好了，你别动
- Hicks。Hurry。- I know.
- 希克斯，快！- 我知道！
- I know！- I mean it！
- 我知道 - 我是说真的！
Newt？Newt，just stay still.
纽伊特，你别动
Almost there.
快好了
No！
不！
Newt！
纽伊特！
No！No！
不！不！
- No！No！No！- Let's go.
- 不！不！不！- 我们走吧
No！No！They don't kill you！
它们不会杀死你！
They-They don't kill you！They-
它们不会杀她
She's alive！She's alive！
她还活着，她还活着！
All right。I believe you。She's alive.
好，我相信你，她还活着
We've got to go。Now！
现在我们得走了！
Go！
走！
- Hicks。- Get it off！
- 希克斯 - 脱下来
Get it off！
快脱掉！
Here.
这儿
Go.
走
Come on。You can make it.
加油，你办得到
Bishop，how much time？
主教，还有多少时间？
Plenty。Twenty-six minutes.
很多，26分钟
- We're not leaving。- We're not？
- 我们还不走 - 是吗？
- Ripley - I don't wanna hear about it，Bishop。She's alive。There's still time.
- 蕾普莉 - 别说了，主教，她还活着，还有时间
In 19 minutes，this area is gonna be a cloud of vapor the size of Nebraska.
再过19分钟这星球会化成烟
Hicks，don't let him leave。We ain't going anywhere.
希克斯，别让他跑了，我们那儿也不去
- See you，Hicks。- Dwayne.
- 我们后会有期了，希克斯 - 杜恩
It's Dwayne.
我叫杜恩
Ellen.
我叫爱伦
Don't be gone long，Ellen.
爱伦，快去快回
Attention。Emergency.
注意，紧急情况
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
全体撤离
You now have 15 minutes…
还剩15分钟…
to reach minimum safe distance.
逃至安全地区
Attention。Emergency.
注意，紧急情况
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
全体撤离
You now have 14 minutes…
还剩14分钟…
to reach minimum safe distance.
逃至安全地区
- Ripley！Ripley！- Newt.
- 蕾普莉！蕾普莉！- 纽伊特！
Grab on to me！Hold on！
抱紧我！抓紧了！
Let's go！
我们走吧！
Behind us！
后面！
Attention。Emergency.
注意！紧急情况！
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
全体撤离
Attention。Emergency.
注意！紧急情况！
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
全体撤离！
You now have four minutes…
剩4分钟…
to reach minimum safe distance.
逃至安全地区
Come on，goddamn it！
快点呀！该死！
Hold on to me！
抱紧我！
Attention。Emergency.
注意！紧急情况！
All personnel must evacuate immediately.
全体撤离！
You now have two minutes…
剩2分钟…
to reach minimum safe distance.
逃至安全地区
No.
糟了！
Bishop，goddamn you！
主教，你真该死！
Close your eyes，baby.
宝贝，把眼睛闭上
Look！
看！
Come on！Come on！
快呀！快呀！
Punch it，Bishop！
主教！全速前进！
It's okay。We're okay.
没事了！安全了！
Hey.
嘿！
We made it.
我们成功了
I knew you'd come.
我就知道你会来
He's gonna be all right。He's just out.
他会复原，他只是昏过去
I had to give him another shot for the pain.
我给他打了一针
We need a stretcher to carry him up to Medical.
我们需要担架送他就医
Okay.
好
I'm sorry if I scared you。That platform wasjust becoming too unstable.
抱歉把你吓坏，起落站不稳定
I had to circle and hope that things didn't get too rough to take you off.
我只好绕飞希望别出问题
Bishop，you did okay.
主教，你做的很好
- I did？- Oh，yeah.
- 真的？- 是的
Go！Move！
走！快走！
No！Here！Here！
不！这边！
Run！
快跑！
Here！
这边！
Get away from her，you bitch！
离她远点，贱货！
Come on！Come on！
来啊！来啊！
Ripley！
蕾普莉！
Bishop！
主教！
- Mommy。- Oh，God！
- 抱我 - 天呀
Not bad for a h-human.
你这人类算是不错
Are we gonna sleep all the way home？
我们是不是要一路睡到家？
- All the way home。- Can I dream？
- 对 - 我能做梦吗？
Yes，honey。I think we both can.
当然，亲爱的，我俩都能做梦
- Sleep tight。- Affirmative.
- 好好睡 - 我同意